# MARIA HELENA AGUIAR MARTINS

### Front-end Developer

#### **Summary**

I have been studying HTML, CSS and Javascript since 2020; Vue and ReactJs since 2021. In 2022, I have started working with Typescript. Also, I have been working as frontend developer since April, 2021, developing mainly with React and Typescript.



+55(11)970809762



lenatinsjs@gmail.com



Mhelena.com.br



https://github.com/HelenaAMartins



https://www.linkedin.com/in/mhelena-martins/

#### **Academic Background**

**2022-currently -** courses about VUE and ReactJs on Udemy

**2020-currently –** courses on front end development on Udemy and Alura

**2014-2016-** Master degree in Literature at Universidade Federal do Ceará

2007-2013- Portuguese and English Language and Literature degree at Universidade Federal do Ceará

## Languages



Portuguese - Native



**English - Advanced** 

#### **Skills**

- ReactJs

- VueJs

- HTML, CSS, JS

- Kanban

- Tailwind

- Git | Github | Bitbucket

- Directus CMS

- Mui Material

#### **Professional Experience**

Magna Sistemas - São Paulo - Brazil

Front-end developer Junior

April, 2022 - currently

4

Lacrei - Brazil - remote

Front-end Junior Voluntário

Setembro, 2022 - February, 2022

**Outroll - Australia - remote** 

Front-end Developer

April, 2021 - September, 2022

•

Colégio Batista Brasileiro - São Paulo

- Brazil

**English Teacher** 

Cultura Inglesa - Fortaleza - Brazil

**English Teacher** 

January, 2014 – December, 2019